Inventory of Student Interest Groups and Student Activities Records AD.RG .009.3-1-1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Student Groups and Student Activities
2015-2023
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG .009.3-1-1
928.7 Megabytes
Biographical / Historical
At New York University Abu Dhabi, student clubs are known as Student Interest Groups (SIGs). In any given semester, there are over 50 active SIGs dedicated to a range of topics and interests, such as the arts and media; cultural and religious identity; outreach and advocacy; student chapters of established professional associations; and sports and recreation. Some SIGs have a longstanding history dating back to the opening of the University in 2010; while some are organized around a particular one-time event and thereafter shortly become defunct. SIGs on campus can submit requests to hold events and other activities, and many have become traditional, hallmark events each year.
There are also a number of organized student networks and groups on campus that are not classified as official "SIGs," but that have been part of the University and continue work in various areas within Student Life. These groups may be involved in volunteering or other types of activities, both internal and external facing.
Scope and Contents
The Records of NYU Abu Dhabi Student Interest Groups (SIGs) and Student Activities includes an accumulation of reports, posters, and other materials directly submitted to the University Archives by student groups, or downloaded by archivists from student engagement platforms.
The largest in terms of volume are the archived SIG semester reports. Each semester SIG leaders are required to submit a report to the Student Engagement and Activities office of the Student Affairs Division. These reports include information on events held, number of members, special projects, and other information about activities. Supplemental information such as flyers and slide decks may also be submitted. In the report, SIGs indicate whether they wish the information to be added to the Univeristy Archives and if yes, whether the records are open for access immediately, restricted for five years, or restricted for ten years (from the date of creation).
SIG leaders may also choose to donate historical materials to be added to their collection in the University Archives. Thus, the collection is arranged and described by SIG, and within each SIG folder, subfolders may include a mix of donated and downloaded records. Semester reports remain described by the leader who submitted, for ease of browsability. Also for ease of browsability, the archivist has added semester date information.
Of note is a cumulative spreadsheet of information about SIG history, 2014-2021, provided by the Office of Student Activities.
Anyone interested in tracing the origins and roots of student organizations and events throughout the history of NYU Abu Dhabi would find this collection a valuable resource.
Related to this collection:
RG 009_3-2-1: Student Life Events: Photos, Videos, and Music RG 023: The Memory Project Oral History Collection
- Student Group Posters, 2014-2018; 345.6 Megabytes for 245 items (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  Scope and Contents
  Posters downloaded by Archives and Special Collections student assistants from different NYUAD Student Group Facebook pages, downloaded between 2018 and 2019, and only reflect what was available for download at that time.
  To donate and transfer copies of posters, NYUAD students and alumni may contact nyuad.archives@nyu.edu to initiate the process.
  - Africa Global, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Anchorage, 2013-2014 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Attitude, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Cake-Up, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Chinese Culture Club, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Ecoherence, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Muslim Student Association, Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Public Health Think Tank (PHTT), Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Strip Club at NYUAD, Fall 2016 - Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Students for Justice in Palestine, Fall 2014; Fall 2016 - Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Tashan, 2018-2019 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - The Design Collective, 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Tower of Babel (Linguistics and Language Learning), Fall 2016 - Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Ukrainian SIG, Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Veggie Might, Fall 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - weSTEM, Spring 2018 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
  - Women's Leadership Network (WLN), Spring 2017 - Fall 2017 (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_Student Group Posters)
- SIG Reports, 2015 - Ongoing; 616.5 Megabytes for 2,496 items (Box E-Records, Folder AD_RG_009.3.1.1_SIG Reports)